Who is it?
何方
Are you aware that the person you are being so rude to is Kongou Mitsuko of Tokiwadai?
私は常盤台中学婚後光子と知っての狼藉ですの
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
I'm so excited!
楽しみですね　学舎の園
The School Garden...
って言ってもさあ
You might say that, but...
それで　ただ女子高が集まってるだけな町でしょう
This city is nothing but a cluster of girls' schools.
An abnormal cluster, at that!
その集まってる学校が普通じゃないんじゃないですか
Everything here is a famous ojou-sama school, not just Tokiwadai!
常盤台中学はもちろん
どれも名立たるお嬢様学校ですよ
そりゃそうだけどさあ
Yeah, but...
We can only visit because Shirai-san invited us.
今日は白井さんたちが招待してくれだから入れますけど
そうじゃなかったら　私みたいな庶民は　一生縁がない場所なんですよ
There's no place for commoners like me otherwise.
Come on, Uiharu, don't act so subservient.
卑屈だな
Huh?
大体初春はさあ
You're such a...
Hey, this is...
あれ　これって
Huh?
Oh, Saten-san, you researched the bakery we're visiting today too!
何だ　佐天さんだって　今日行くケーキ屋さんチェックしてるじゃないですか
B-but... it's Pasticceria Manicagni!
だ　だって　パスティジェリアマリガワリンなんだよ
厳選された素材を
They use hand picked ingredients and bake the cheesecake exactly like they do in Italy.
イタリア本国と寸分トランイピリアケーキだチーズケーキを
Naturally it's a masterpiece!
まさに芸術品で書いてあるでしょう
これは前から一度食べてみたかったのに
I've always wanted to try it.
日本じゃ学舎の園にしか出店してないだもん
The only branch of this shop in Japan is in School Garden.
佐天さんって、意外とみいはあなんですね
Saten-san, you're actually rather lowbrow...
次は学舎の園入り口　学舎の園入り口です
The next stop is the School Garden entrance.
School Garden entrance.
Huh, the bus got here earlier than scheduled.
ありゃ～　バス予定より早くついちゃったね
大丈夫ですよ　三　二　一
No big deal.
3- 2- 1
Huh?
うわ～～　相変わらずこの町の天気予報は完璧だね
The weather forecast is as precise as usual, I see.
予報というより
Well, it's not really a forecast. More like a prediction through computation, I'd say.
演算によって確定された未来の事象読み上げっていると言うほうが正確ですね
I think it'd be cuter if they got it wrong every now and then.
たまには外すぐらいの茶目っ気があっても良いと思うな　私は
それより　早く行きましょう
Well, whatever, let's hurry!
Shirai Kuroko-san, a first year at Tokiwadai Junior High invited us.
常盤台中学一年の白井黒子さんに招待された
初春飾利と
I'm Uiharu Kazari, and this is...
佐天涙子です
Saten Ruiko.
You're clear. Please proceed.
はい　結構です
This city is so cute!
何て可愛いらしい町なんでしょう
Even the crosswalks and the traffic lights have different designs!
横断歩道や信号まで
全部外とデザイン違うだもん
It's so exquisite.
凝ってるよね
It really feels like we're in a foreign country!
本当に　よその国に来たみたいです
True.
だね
Huh?
Oh.
Hmm?
I think we're attracting attention.
あの
私たちなにやれ注目されてませんか
Huh?
あ　この格好じゃない
Oh?
Maybe it's how we're dressed?
It's probably not often that they get guests from schools outside the district.
ここのじゃ外の学校の生徒が珍しいんだよ　きっと
I guess.
Oh, I see.
お～　なるほど
やばっ　もう時間だよ
Oh no! It's already time!
えっ　ああ　本当だ
You're right!
Let's hurry up!
ほら　急ごう
Oh!
遅いわね　二人とも
Those two are late.
待ち合わせはここでいいのよね
We're in the right place, right?
ええ～うちの学校が見たいって言うからわざわざ校門前にしましたのに
Yes.
They said they wanted to see our school, so we decided to meet them in front of the school gates.
まったく　お姉さまをお待たせするなんて　あの子達
Sheesh. How can they keep Onee-sama waiting like this?
Oh, here they come.
来た　来た
Um...
What happened?
何なんですの
Nothing...
いいえ　水溜りで　ちょっと
I had some trouble with a puddle...
I see.
急に着替えようと言われましても　それぐらいしか用意できませんでしたわ
I'm afraid I don't have any other clothes on hand for you to wear.
Oh, don't worry about it.
いいえ　十分です
Huh?
How's the size?
サイズはどう
It's perfect, but...
丁度いいんですけど
スカートが短くて　すうすうします
the skirt is too short and breezy...
Saten-san, I want to try one on too!
佐天さんだけ　ずるいです
Huh?
Oh, right, you should swap with me!
そうだ　私の制服と交換しましょう　そうしましょう
My thoughts exactly!
それがいい
Let's get to it!
Yours is too small! I'll never fit into it!
小さすぎて　無理だってば
Fine, then I'll just step into a puddle too!
じゃ私も水溜まりで
Cut it off!
止めなさいって
Just a little!
ちょっとだけでいいですから
Hey, Uiharu!
ほら　初春
I sent your dirty uniform to the cleaners.
汚れた制服はクリーニングに出して置いたから
Go pick it up on your way home.
帰りに寄ってね
If it's too much trouble for you, I will have it delivered to your dorm.
面倒でしたら　あなた方の寮まで届けさせますの
Wow. Just what I'd expect from Tokiwadai.
うわ～～　さすが常盤台
メイドさんですか
You have maids? Do the maids do it for you?
やっぱりメイドさんがやってくれるんですか
Calm down!
落ち着け
Hmm... this Strawberry Crostata thing, or...
えん～　イチゴのクロスタータってやつか
No, no. The Monte Bianco thing looks nice too.
いやいや
モンテビアンコって言うのもおいしそう
Oh, and this Chocolata looks pretty good as well.
このチョコレータってのも捨て難い
Do you really need to make a fuss over this?
そんなに悩むようなことですの
Well, I had planned to get some cheesecake, so...
まあ　あたしはチーズケーキって決まってましたから
We're gonna be here all day. Hurry up and decide.
早くしないと　日が暮れちゃうよう
P-please wait for a second.
ちょっと待ってください
はい　はい
Hello?
Yes?
Huh?
はい　分かりました
Yes, I understand.
A summons?
呼び出しですの
Yes...
はい
タイミングの悪い事この上なしですわね
At the worst possible timing.
I'll get Uiharu-san's to go.
初春さんの分　テークアウトしとくね
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
We're leaving, Uiharu.
行きますわよ　初春
Yes!
はい
慌しいわね
They're always in a hurry.
Then, we should...
じゃ私たちは
Oh...
Excuse me. I need to go to the restroom.
あの　私　ちょっとお手洗いに
Geez
まったく　せっかくの非番の土曜日だと言うのに
It was our Saturday off, too.
Ouch.
あ　った
いた
Ouch.
到着早々ぼやかないの
Hey, don't complain from the get-go.
I'm sorry, Komori-sempai.
すみません　固法先輩
So, why'd you call us out here
で　呼び出して理由は何ですの
昨日の放課後から夜にかけて
Six Tokiwadai students have been attacked since yesterday.
常盤台の生徒ばかりが六人  連続して襲われる事件があったの
しかも　すべて学舎の園の中で
And it all happened within the School Garden.
Huh?
What?
Only students at Level 3 or higher attend Tokidawadai Junior High.
<Level 3>
常盤台中学には　强能力者以上の能力者しかいない
They're only targeting students from Tokiwadai, and they're also managing to beat them, so...
それを狙い
いとも簡単に倒していることから
相当の能力者ってことですの
whoever's doing it must be rather powerful.
可能性は高いわね
That's certainly a possibility.
ただ能力は不明　被害者は全員
However, we don't know what their ability is.
Also, all of the victims were knocked unconscious with a stun gun.
スタンガンで昏倒させられているの
What happened to them after that...?
それで意識を失った被害者は
写真があるけど
We have photos, but...
They're horrible.
ひどいよ　見るんだったら覚悟しなさい
If you want to see them, then you had better be prepared.
Hmm...
Her tea is going to get cold.
紅茶冷めちゃうよ
I decided to join Judgment of my own accord. I am prepared.
風紀委員に志願した以上　覚悟はできてますの
私もです
Me too.
I see...
そう　だったら
Then...
Huh!?
Saten-san?
佐天さん
H-Huh?
H-Hey!
ちょっと　佐天さん
Saten-san!
被
盯
上
的
常
盘
台
Tokiwadai
Under
Fire
A Certain Scientific Railgun
常盤台がり
Hunting for Tokiwadai students?
I see.
そうか うちの制服を着てたせいで
It must be because she was wearing our uniform, then...
具合はどうなんですか
How is she?
She'll probably recover if she rests for a while. Apparently her injuries weren't too bad.
体のほうはたいした事なくて
暫く横になれば大丈夫だろうって
But...
ただ
犯人の目星はついてるの
Do we have any suspects?
Not yet.
まだですの
少々厄介な能力者のようでしって
It seems to be a rather troublesome ability, though.
Troublesome? How?
厄介って
目に見えないんです
She's invisible.
Huh?
I'm not lying!
本当ですわ
私何にも見ていません
I didn't see anything!
えっと ですが
Um... but...
監視カメラの映像ですと
The CCTV captured a video...
それでも ほんとに 見ておりませんの
I don't care!
I really didn't see her!
Oh...
Oh.
被害者には見えない犯人ね
A suspect invisible only to the victim, eh?
最初は光学操作系の能力者を疑ったのですが
We suspected that she was using an optical manipulation ability, but...
姿を完全に消せるの能力者は学園都市に47人を持つ
there are only 47 people in the city who can become completely invisible.
けど その全員にアリバイがあって
And all 47 of them have an alibi.
それ以前に監視カメラには映ってるんでしょう
Moreover, she shows up in the video taken by the CCTV.
光学操作系って言うのは ちょっと違うんじゃない
Maybe she isn't an optical manipulation type.
そうなんですの
Yeah, maybe.
あ 鳩
Oh, a pigeon.
Huh?
白井さん見なかったんですか
Shirai-san, you didn't see it?
そんな物 気付きませんでしたわ
No, I didn't see anything of the sort.
You didn't notice...
気付かない
初春さん ちょっと調べてほしいんだけど
Uiharu-san!
I want you to check something.
Here it is.
ありました
<Dummy Check>
能力名は虚仮検験
The ability's name is Dummy Check.
It prevents people from noticing that you're watching them.
対象物を見ているという認識そのもの阻害する能力です
該当する能力者は一名
There's one ability user who can use this...
関所中学校二年 重福省帆
Jufuku Miho, a second year student from Sekisho Junior High School.
She's the one!
そいつですわ
But she's only a Level 2!
<Level 2>
でも この人异能力者です
自分の存在を完全に消せるほどの力ではないと実験データにあります
The data we have on her states that she's not good enough to conceal herself completely.
Sigh, I thought we were on the right track there.
いい線いってると思ったんだけど
I...
あたし
Saten-san,
佐天さん
you don't have to get up...
無理しない で
Huh?
Eh?!
W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-Wha-
なん なん なん なん なんで
Saten-san, stay strong!
佐天さん 気を確かに
W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-W-Wha-
You must be in shock.
ショックだよね そうりゃあ
You could hide them if you had long enough bangs...
せめて このくらい前髪があったら隠せましたのにね
Bangs?
前髪
T-This is her!
こいつだ
Huh?
あなた 犯人を見たんですの
You saw the suspect?
はい
Yes...
あの時
Just now...
I saw her in the mirror...
鏡の中に 確かに
So, she shows up in mirrors and on CCTV...
鏡に監視カメラ
なるほど そういうことか
I see. So that's how it works.
認識できなくするのは直接肉眼で見てる相手に限られるんだ
She can only make herself invisible to the human eye.
I must have my revenge for these eyebrows!
この眉毛の恨み 晴らさねい置くべきか
やるよ 初春
We're gonna screw her over, Uiharu.
はい？
Huh?
This is amazing.
なんか凄いね
こうでもしないと ここにある端末じゃ処理が追いつかないんです
I have to do it like this. The terminals here take too long to process things.
School Garden isn't under the jurisdiction of the 177th Branch, after all.
それより 学舎の園は一七七支部の管轄じゃないですけど
大丈夫なんですか
Are we okay?
上からの許可 取り付けましたわ
I got permission from the executives.
ようしゃ
Okay. Blow it up, Uiharu!
初春 どんどん行ってみようか
はいはい
Okay.
Kaboom!
ドン
All CCTV cameras in School Garden online. 2458 total connected.
学舎の園の監視カメラ全二千四百五十ハ台
接続終えました
Wow.
待ってろうよ 前髪女
Just you wait, bangs lady!
必ず見つけ出してやるからな
I'm gonna smoke you out!
約束のケーキ 忘れないでくださいよ
Don't forget the cakes you promised me.
You can have as many as you want, I don't care!
三個でも 四個でも 好きなだけ食べてよし
はい
Great!
Too many.
多すぎるわね
そうですか
Is it?
え～～大丈夫ですよ
Aww... it'll be fine.
ケーキの話じゃありませんわ
She's not talking about the cake.
Eh?
初春 エリアEからHと JとNには無視ですは
Uiharu, ignore Areas E through H... and J and N as well.
Oh, right.
はい
あの辺りは常盤台から一番遠い場所
Those areas are the furthest from Tokiwadai, so our students rarely go there.
ですからうちの生徒はほとんどいかないですの
I see.
じゃ人通りの多いところも後回しね
Let's leave the more crowded areas for later, too.
Eh?
Why is that?
何でですか
犯人の服装
Look at how the suspect was dressed.
学舎の園じゃかなり目立つと思わない
She'd really stand out in School Garden.
Oh. That's true.
確かに
人目のあるところではずっと能力を使っていると
So, she's probably using her ability continuously whenever people are around.
多分ね
Probably.
けど 能力を永遠に使い続けることはできない
But she can't use her ability forever.
どこか瞳につかないところで息を潜めている
So, she's hiding somewhere where no one can see her?
正解
Correct.
That means...
という事は
見つけた
Found you!
あたしの可愛い眉毛の仇 きっちり取らせてもらうからね
I'll be taking revenge on you for these cute eyebrows of mine!
Oh!
She really did disappear!
本当に消えた
Hey, don't gawk at her!
感心してる場合じゃありません 追ってください
Just chase her!
Oh yeah...
おっと そうだっだ
Ouch!
痛い
What's the matter?
どうしたんの
今何かにぶつかったんだけど
I just hit something...
ちょっとごめん
Excuse me!
Hey!
ちょっと
Around here...
このあたり
O-Ouch!
Hey!
Wha-?
風紀委員ですの 大人しくお縄についてくださいまし
It's Judgment!
Stop resisting! You're under arrest!
Well, of course you won't.
って つくわけないですわね
初春 波をお願いしますわ
Uiharu, navigation please.
はいはい
Sure thing.
Leave the alley and take a left.
路地を出って左  三番街に入ってください
Please enter the 3rd street district.
了解ですの
Understood.
初春
Uiharu.
はい
Okay.
Why?
何で
鬼ごっこは 終わりよ
This game of tag is... over now.
どうして
Why?
<Dummy Check>
何で虚仮検験が効かないの
Why isn't my Dummy Check working on you?
さあね
Who knows?
これだから 常盤台の連中は
This is why I hate Tokiwadai people!
Eh?
残念
Too bad.
私こういうの効かないんだよね
That stuff doesn't work against me.
Um...
手加減はしたからね
I did limit myself.
<Antiskill>
初春 容疑者を拘束したと警備員に連絡してくださいな
Uiharu.
Tell the Antiskills that we have taken the suspect into custody.
Right.
はい
お疲れ様
Good work!
So then...
さあってと
どんな眉毛にしてあげましょうか
What sort of eyebrows would you like...?
Noo!
いや
えっと
Um...
It's weird, right?
可笑しいでしょう
Huh?
は？
What?
Um...
あの
笑いなさいよ
Laugh at me!
Just go ahead and laugh!
笑えばいいわ
あの人みたいに
Just like he did!
あの人
Who's he?
春
It was during the spring...
私は麗らかの日差しの中でまどろんでいた
I was enjoying the warm sun.
I was so innocent then.
幸せな時間は いつまでも続くと無邪気に信じていた
I thought those happy times could last forever...
けど
But...
Spring ended.
春は終わった
All of a sudden.
唐突に
どうして そんなに常盤台のお嬢様がいいの
Why?
Are Tokiwadai ojou-samas so much better than I am?
別にそう言う訳じゃ
Well, no, but...
じゃ 何で
Then why?
だって お前の眉毛って 変
Because your eyebrows are...
Weird...
I hate that guy who dumped me!
私を捨てたあの男が憎い
私から彼を奪った常盤台の女が憎い
I hate those Tokiwadai women for stealing him from me!
そして 何より この世の眉毛全てが憎い
And... most of all, I hate every pair of eyebrows in the world!
So, I decided to make all of them as weird as mine!
だから 皆面白い眉毛にしてやろうと思ったのよ
Um...
えっと
ごめん
Sorry...
途中から話が見えないや
You kinda lost me somewhere along the line.
Uhh...
なにを
What?
Huh?
どうしたの さあ 笑いなさいよ
What's the matter?
Go ahead and laugh!
えっ えっと
Umm... Er...
変じゃないよ
They're not weird.
Yeah, that's it... uh...
そのぐらい その
そう 丁度いいチャームポイントだって
Yeah, they're your charm point!
あたしはそれ好きだな
I like 'em!
Eh?
罪な女ですの
What a sinful woman...
Huh!?
Umm...
あの 手紙 書いてもいいですか
Can I write to you?
はい
Sure...
She was able to hide herself completely.
彼女 完璧に姿を消してたよね
<Level 2>
そういえば　 异能力者だと言う話でしたのに
Actually, wasn't she supposed to be a Level 2?
That's strange.
変ですわね
Maybe the database is wrong?
まさか バンクのデータが間違ってるとか
N-No way...
ま まさか
どうなってんのよ
What's going on here!?
Huh?
他の被害者の方もですか
It happened to the other victims too!
Well, it looks like she used a special ink developed by a university in the 10th Academic District.
それが 第十学の大学で開発された特殊なインクらしくでね
They said it's not gonna come off for a week or two.
一週間は絶対に消えないって
Saten-san,
佐天さん また帽子用意しましょうか
should I buy you a hat?
That eyebrow woman!
あの眉毛女
やっぱり  落書きしてやればよかった
I should have scribbled all over her!
Please calm down, Saten-san!
佐天さん 気を確かに
Argh! What should I do?
どうすればいいのよ
Dear My Friend Every day & night
Always be with you
Dear My Friend every day & night
話しても　まだまだ　足りないまま
夕焼けが　街を染めてゆく
思うように　なかなか　いかない…って
気づいたら　一緒に　泣いていた
恋も　夢も　花も　虹も　風も
ぜんぶ掴もうよ
ダイジョウブ！　元気出して
私がそばにいるから
今日のミス　悔やむより　今　乗り越えて
ダイジョウブ！　迷わないで
まだ見ぬ未来へと向かって
ずっと　歩いてゆこう
Dear My Friend every day & night
Always be with you
Next Episode
ねぇ 初春 雪駄婆って知ってる？
Hey Uiharu, do you know about the Setta Babaa?
都
市
传
说
Urban
Myths
せ 雪駄婆？
Setta Babaa?
雪駄を履いたお婆さんが 時速１００キロ追い掛けて来るんだって
She's a granny who chases you at 100 km/h in a saddle!
怖い
How terrifying!
しかも全裸で
And she's naked!
気持ち悪！
How disgusting!